CARLOS FERNÁNDEZ SAN MILLÁN

@ carlos.fernandez.san.millan@gmail.com

**** +49 151 407 30 113

₩ 18th June 1977

cormite.com in linkedin.com/in/carlosfernandezsanmillan

y cormite

github.com/cormite



Las Updated: 9th Mar, 2020

Systems and Virtualization Engineer with 10+ years of experience in international IT enterprise environments. Managed large scale virtualization and storage infrastructures, proficient in VMware and NetApp with deep passion for enterprise-wide management and optimization. Ability to work as a team, experience in international multidisciplinary groups, primarily in education and research environments, leadership and fast learning ability. Always interested in challenging projects, as well as close interaction with manufacturers.

EXPERIENCE

Systems and Virtualization Engineer

European Molecular Biology Laboratory

October 2018 - Ongoing

♥ Heidelberg, Germany

Systems Engineer

European Molecular Biology Laboratory

October 2012 - October 2018

♥ Heidelberg, Germany

- Responsible of VMware Cluster (26 physical hosts & 650 VMs)
 Migration from ESX 4.1 to ESXi 5.1, 5.5, 6.0, 6.5 and 6.7 (VMware vSphere Enterprise Plus). Consolidation of VMware Clusters in Heidelberg, Rome, and Barcelona; managed from Heidelberg's HQ. Responsible of the High Performance, GPU Driven, VDI infrastructure. Planned, configured and administered vSAN for the VDI cluster. In charge of the virtualization backup with Veeam Backup & Replication.
- NetApp administration [Data ONTAP until 9.6] [14 nodes ≈ 5.5 PB]
 Management of volumes, qtrees, policies (export, QoS, quota, snapshots), network interfaces. Monitoring the 14 node cluster to ensure optimal performance. Migrated qtrees and volumes from the legacy 7-Mode cluster to Data ONTAP.
- Other responsibilities

Datacenter management. Linux Support. Management and support of application such as Alfresco and Owncloud. Development of tools in python to consume APIs. Management of central infrastructure with Foreman, Puppet and Git. Monitoring infrastructure with Zabbix.

IT Manager

Digital Arts & Designers, S.L.

Las Palmas de Gran Canaria, Spain

Management of IT Projects. Linux Administration. Server Management. Networking Management. Monitoring and keeping infrastructure in optimal conditions. Responsible of purchasing technical equipment and keeping good relations with providers.

Freelance System Administrator

FIFA

m June 2010 - July 2010

Pretoria & Johannesburg, South Africa

System administrator of Referee Channel, an e-learning platform based on web and video-streaming for FIFA Refereeing Department during the 2010 FIFA World Cup.

Previous Jobs / Companies

m June 2002 - May 2010

- Jan 2009 May 2010 | Systems administrator, Neuronal Software S.L.
- Mar 2008 Dec 2008 | Media Producer & System Administrator, Univ. of Las Palmas de G.C.
- Oct 2005 Nov 2005 | Technical officer, Gran Canaria Espacio Digital
- Sep 2004 Jun 2005 | Consultant, Gran Canaria Campus junior entrepreneurship
- Jun 2002 Jul 2002 | Project Manager & Developer, La Provincia, Diario de Las Palmas
- Sep 1997 Sep 1999 | Laboratory Assistant, University of San Francisco

STRENGTHS

Linux Administration

VMware Administration

NetApp Administration

Veeam Backup & Recovery

vSAN

scripting

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Virtualization: VMware vSphere, VMware Horizon, OpenNebula, oVirt
- Storage: NetApp, QNap, Synology
- Backup: TSM, Veeam
- ERP: SAP
- Network: Fortigate, Extreme Networks, Netgear, Linksys, MicroTik, TP-Link, Ubiquity, ZyXEL, D-Link,
- Operating Systems: RedHat, CentOS, Debian, Ubuntu, SuSE
- Services: LDAP, DHCP, DNS
- Automation: Foreman, Puppet, Ansible, Scripting
- Containers: Docker
- Container's Orchestration: Kubernetes

CERTIFICATES

VMware Certified Associate - Data Center Virtualization

VMware

♦ Heidelberg, Germany

Credential ID 12011513-BE5E-90361323E2E7

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Technical Engineering in Computer Science

University of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria

2000 - 2005

♀ Las Palmas de Gran Canaria

Activities and Societies: Gran Canaria Campus Junior Enterpreneurship

BSc Computer Science

School of Arts and Science, University of San Francisco

1996 - 2000

♀ San Francisco, California

Activities and Societies: USF Men's Soccer Team.

Summer Courses

University of California, Berkeley

Summer 1998

Perkeley, California

Physics and Computer Architecture.

Professional Instructor-Led Training

- 03-2019 Kubernetes Fundaments & Operations Bundle (Amazic via Evenbrite)
- 09-2016 VMware vRealize Automation: Install, Configure, Manage [V7.0] (VMWAREVRICM7) (QA Limited)
- 05-2016 VMware vSphere: Install, Configure, Manage plus Optimize and Scale Fast Track [V6.0] (VMware)
- 07-2015 IBM Tivoli Storage Manager 7.1.1 Implementation and Administration (QA Limited)
- 10-2014 Clustered Data ONTAP 8.2 Administration [NA DCADM] (Fast Lane)
- 11-2013 Data ONTAP 7-Mode Administration [NA D7ADM] (Fast Lane)

Online Training

- 03-2020 | Essential Container Concepts
- 02-2020 | Beginner's Guide to Containers and Orchestration
- 02-2020 | Ansible Quick Start
- 09-2018 | Puppet Quick Start
- 09-2018 | DevOps Essentials
- 08-2018 | Mastering The Linux Command Line
- 08-2018 | VIM The Improved Editor
- 08-2018 | Git Quick Start
- 12-2013 | Data ONTAP 7-Mode Fundamentals
- 07-2013 | Data ONTAP 8.1.1 7-Mode New Features
- 07-2013 | Data ONTAP License Key Replacement Scenarios
- 07-2013 | Introduction to NetApp Products
- 07-2013 | NetApp Transition Fundamentals
- 07-2013 | Technical Overview of Licensing in Data ONTAP 8.2
- 07-2013 | What's New in Data ONTAP 8.2 Licensing

SOFT SKILLS

Learning Potential Team Work

Organization Flexibility

Professionalism Responsibility

MultiTasking Work Under Pressure

Initiative Problem Solving Proactive

Curiosity

LANGUAGES

Social Skills

Spanish - Native English - Full Prof. Proficiency Galician Portuguese German



OTHERS

- Driving License B
- SSI Diver Level 3 (MID 312710)

11-2016 - Specialty Diver

11-2016 - Dry Suit Diver

10-2016 - Enriched Air Nitrox

09-2016 - Perfect Buoyancy

11-2015 - Mission Deep Ocean Ranger

11-2010 - Open Water Diver

REFERENCES

Dr. Rupert Lück, Head of IT.

@ European Molecular Biology Laboratory

■ lueck@embl.de

Prof. Dr. Cayetano Guerra Artal, Professor of Computer Science & Artificial Inteligence

② University of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria

PROJECTS

Referee Channel

Digital Arts & Designers S.L.

m October 2010 - October 2012

♀ International

- Referee Channel is a classification system of all game situations occurred in competition's matches which can be consulted from anywhere in the world without having to duplicate resources, allowing to establish a reliable and proactive communication system between all members of an organization. I was in charge of the server infrastructure and correct operation of the application.
- This tools was used by several institutions and during several competitions in these countries: Colombia, Spain, South Africa, Russia, USA
 - 4th South American Under 20 Futsal World Cup Championship. Itagüí (Colombia)
 - I-International Planet of Football, and Technology organized by Royal Spanish Soccer Federation. Madrid (Spain)
 - 2010 FIFA World Cup South Africa. Pretoria, (South Africa)
 - Russian Soccer Federation. Moscow (Russia)
 - CONCACAF Gold Cup 2010. New York (USA)

112 Accesible

University of Las Palmas & Cátedra Telefónica

June 2011 - November 2011

♀ Las Palmas de Gran Canaria

• 112 Accessible is a winning project of the prize from Cátedra Telefónica developed in the University of Las Palmas to help the emergency services to be more accessible to people who can't contact the 112 Emergency Center by voice call. I organized and produced the contents for 112 Accessible

IESCampus

Neuronal Software S.L.

m June 2008 - June 2010

♀ Las Palmas de Gran Canaria, Spain

• IESCampus is an innovative educational website where you find all the resources necessary to achieve quality training in Secondary Education and Baccalaureate. IESCampus includes the full syllabus of the subjects, providing an excellent educational tool for both students and their teachers

Prometeo

University of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria

July 2007 - June 2010

♦ Las Palmas de Gran Canaria, Spain

• E-learning application for the University of Las Palmas de Gran Canaria, based on web and video streaming.